foreign
[Music]
the reason why there isn't even a word
for hot flash in Japanese as I explored
my last video
approximately 80 percent of
perimenopausal and post-menopausal women
surveyed and choose to try natural means
to deal with symptoms and the single
most common approach was soy but does it
work
outside of an Asian context soy milk
maybe a greater source of isoflavones
than soy foods and that seems already
made for randomized trial against dairy
milk or another plant milk control
soy milk consumption has been associated
with fewer hot flashes and night sweats
and skim milk with worse menopausal
symptoms but when actually put to the
test against each other there does not
appear to be any difference there have
been studies showing that randomizing
women to soy milk can reduce hot flashes
and vaginal symptoms as much as 70
compared to the control group but
without a placebo control we're not sure
how much of that is the placebo effect
to truly blind study subjects soy
isoflavones were extracted out and
stuffed into capsules to be pinned
against identical looking sugar pill
Placebo capsules more than a dozen such
clinical studies have been performed
randomized double-blind
placebo-controlled trials and indeed the
equivalent of about two servings of soy
Foods a day worth reduced hot flash
symptoms by about 20 more than Placebo
and hot flash severity by around 25
percent more than Placebo compared to
more like a 30 to 40 net reduction from
estrogen hormone therapy
soy isoflavones have also been shown to
improve other menopausal concerns
including vaginal dryness bone loss
memory and cognitive functions more
generally as well as depression there
have been a few trials in which soy was
pitted head to head against hormone
therapy one found their efficacy
comparable in terms of reducing hot
flashes muscle and joint pain vaginal
dryness in the other hormones work twice
as well a 54 reduction in hot flash
scores taking the standard estrogen
progesterone combination compared to 24
over Placebo in the soy isoflavon group
not only did the hormones work better
but they can work quicker three months
are required for soy isofy bones to
achieve half their maximal effect
whereas the same is achieved after just
three weeks with estrogen of course soy
has the benefit of no increased risk of
cancer and clots in fact if anything a
reduction in breast cancer risks
throughout the lifespan and lower risk
of cardiovascular disease
the bottom line wrote One consensus
panel of experts is that soy can be
considered a first line treatment for
menopausal hot flash and night sweat
symptoms one convenient whole food
source of soy is soy nuts which are dry
roasted soybeans Harvard Medical
school's center of excellence in women's
health funded a randomized crossover
study of a half cup of unsalted soy nuts
a day divided into three or four
portions and space throughout the day
and achieved a 50 reduction in hot
flashes within two weeks
what's inconvenient about soy nuts is
the formation of advanced glycation and
products in the roasting process though
about four times less than that of
roasted real nuts or other roasted
legumes and 10 times less than a serving
of something like roasted chicken but
something like edamame or canned
soybeans would be better some menopausal
women use isoflavone supplements but
most just add soy foods to their diet I
think that's the way to go supplement
mislabeling contamination issues aside
the isolated isoflavones have been shown
to improve artery function and decrease
high blood pressure soy foods can also
lower LDL cholesterol which may explain
the lower Associated cardiovascular
disease risk besides the lower breast
cancer risk soy eaters are also less
likely to get prostate cancer colorectal
cancer
and lung cancer
in a previous video I noted that those
eating plant-based tend to have
significantly fewer hot flash type
symptoms what if you combined a
plant-based diet and soybeans
two randomized controlled trials found
that reduced fat plant-based diets with
a daily half cup serving of cooked
soybeans can reduce the number of
serious hot flashes by 84 to 88 percent
within 12 weeks overall most randomized
the plant-based group ended up free of
moderate to severe hot flashes compared
to about 95 percent still suffering in
the control group
[Music]
thank you